PRATEEK AGRAWAL

L +91 7464847884

prateekagrawal89760@gmail.com

Mumbai

bit.ly/prateekagrawal

TECHNICAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

B.Tech

GLA University

Computer Science CGPA- 7.2

Intermediate

UP Board

Percentage- 82

High School

UP Board

Percentage- 74

FIND ME ONLINE

- in LinkedIn⊠ @agrawal-prateek
- Github
 ☐ @agrawal-prateek
- (ii) Hackerrank @unknownbody

SUMMARY

Experienced in a product based company as Software Engineer, where my day to day responsibilities includes writing APIs & services, development of application frontend & standalone applications, and writing complex SQL queries.

I've strong OOP design skills, solid knowledge of system design, flexible in learning new technologies, experience with Agile & client-server architecture development, web applications, web services, APIs and passionate to work with architects on complex systems.

I have good problem solving skills and strong knowledge in algorithms & data structures.

EXPERIENCE

Media.net

Software Developer (Mar 2020 - Present)

Working on Backend, Frontend and Database. The day to day responsibility includes creation of new features, debugging and enhancements of existing ones. worked on the following projects so far-

Ad Rendering

Worked on multiple projects simultaneously, created some from scratch. The system's purpose was to show ads for publishers (website & apps).

- POC to know the optimal way for ad-rendering by analysing existing systems of media.net and other bidders like google
- Decision of Database structure, creation of tables and procedures
- Created a system by which business developers can create ad-templates, an automation runs and compiles them to frontend code, and makes them ready to be rendered on enduser's devices
- Created a STL Compiler whose purpose was to provide feasibility for ad-creation. No-one writes HTML for ads, templates are created, which then are compiled by backend
- Created another system which runs and creates ads & their assets, pushes them on S3 to be used by bidder
- Created manager-script, which is written in JS. It is responsible to show ads on end-user's devices
- Worked on mad-max, a bidder, which bids for DSP services, and returns ads after bidding
- Created system to optimize & validation automation for ads.
- Some other features to decide, which ad to make live

Rangers

Created a system which takes very less input, and creates bulk-ads. After this system, It can create thousands of ads within few minutes.

Taken

The whole purpose for this project is re-marketing of ads (purchase in cheap from google, yahoo and more), and use multi-click model for ads to make profit.

- Created feature for create Audiences for Adgroups.
- Created feature for Targetings, which are used to target audiences, devices, domains, location... etc
- An ad-optimization interface, which shows campaigns, ad-groups & ads, and user can change bids & budget, features like daywise-stats for ads etc.
- ☑ Created Ad-studio, which can create ads within 30 seconds of UI interaction

DataTool

Created a system, where existing DB tables can be imported and make changes there. The purpose was to handle things like-

- ☑ Developers and BDs can assess tables without knowing password
- Multi-level permissions on tables
- No-need to create more procs for simple data-fetching & writing, a generic datatool-api will work at all
- Show only non-confidential columns, autogeneration logic need not to be exposed

Cloudreach

Software Engineer (Jan 2020 - Mar 2020)

Worked on pre-cloud, developed following feature:

- Created "upload CSV" feature for bulk update on asset and nodes for the cloud resources
- Writing Java services to be consumed by UI
- Conversion of Postgres procedures into Java services
- Created a helper service to validate the OS for "GCP Velostrata" for semistructured data without analytics

Software Developer (Jan 2019 - Jan 2020)

Worked on the following applications and features:

AWS Cost Explorer

Developed "AWS Cost Explorer" to be used to analyze cost, usage, and performance for AWS resources. The features includes-

- ☑ Developed Inventory Explorer, budget vs actual cost, and prebuilt top reports
- Feature for user-defined reports
- ✓ Worked on looker (A BI tool)
- Writing complex SQL queries

Hierarchy Builder

Developed "Hierarchy Builder" to manage user's cloud resources efficiently

- ☑ Developed delete, edit, creation of group and hierarchies for Hierarchy Builder
- Features for user assignment to the groups
- ☑ Developed features for spend management and Budget for cloud resources

Other tasks

Worked on some different tasks according to company's requirement

- Developed backend APIs using spring-boot to show data on different frontend applications including cost explorer and manage (A Cloudreach Application)
- Writing complex SQL with backend services
- ☑ Conversion of PL/SQL procedures into Java backend middleware
- ☑ Developed standalone application to run designer task on cloud using Python
- ☑ Big shoutout to company on completion 37 tasks within a sprint.

PROJECTS

Antitheft Pro □

A security system which is **patented** and used Python to develop

Abacuscea [☑]

A website developed on Node.Js for hosting events and media

Robot [☑]

IoT project developed using Google APIs, Python

Credential Generator

A web application developed for IIIT using PHP

Security system controller [□]

Web Application developed using Python and Flask

Cloud drive [☑]

Linux software developed using Python

Grub modifier [☑]

Linux software developed using Python

Te Amo[☑]

A restaurant website developed as a freelancer

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure

Coursera, Credential ID KV7EDLB59PMX

Acadmic Credential Generator <a>□

Credential ID IIITM/DIR/Reco/21042018

React - The Complete Guide(incl. React Router & Redux)[□]

Udemy, Credential ID UC-OI16WE9B

ACHIEVEMENTS

Owns a **patented** product Antitheft and received a fund of Rs 2.5 Lakhs from IEDC (Innovation and Entrepreneurship Development Centre).